Megan Walker - Lange

Oldbury, B68

07906239175 / meg.walker56@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/megan-walker-lange-b5a06aa4/

Summary

I am an enthusiastic and motivated candidate with previous experience working with social media and digital communication. My background is in Illustration and I have a keen interest in design and enjoy using these skills to produce clean, considered pages and applications. I am currently in the process of completing a Frontend Skills Bootcamp with the University of Birmingham.

Skills

Photoshop -Bootstrap -Indesign

Microsoft Suite -JavaScript -Customer Service

HTML5 -MailChimpCSS -Wordpress

Work History

Pharmacy Administrator – Healthcare at Home (August 2014 - March 2015, Burton-on-Trent)

The requirements of this role were mainly processing and inputting data regarding patient prescriptions, updating files, sorting and scanning daily post.

Receptionist/Administrator - Birmingham Botanical Gardens (March 2015-February 2019, Edgbaston, Birmingham)

My main duties within this role were to help run the front desk with ticket sales, customer queries and cash handling. This experience was invaluable for developing good customer service skills and always being conscious of being a good representative of the company. However, I was also given the additional responsibility to help with other administrative duties, including sorting and processing tickets sales for events, managing membership databases and updating the company website. I regularly used Microsoft suite for these tasks and started to get to grips with WordPress. I became familiar with creating and updating event pages, setting up online ticket sales and creating sub-menus to navigate across the website. In addition I also wrote an instruction manual on how to use the Wordpress site for my colleagues before leaving the role.

Franny's Father is a Feminist – Freelance Illustration Project (2018)

I was commissioned in the summer of 2017 to illustrate the picture book 'Franny's Father is a Feminist', published by POW! Kids Books and written by Rhonda Leet. This was a challenging commission with a short deadline, which I was able to meet. This was my first

major illustration project and I am pleased to say we received a Kirkus Starred review. https://powkidsbooks.com/books/franny-s-father-is-a-feminist/ (link)

The Big Hug – Author/Illustrator (2021)

In 2020 I was commissioned by POW! Kids Books to write and illustrate a book in response to the pandemic. I wrote 'The Big Hug' as a way for children to understand the resilience of friendship. For this project I took a more active role in promoting it on publication, taking part in author events at local bookshops, conducting Zoom interviews and live readings. I also set up a competition to win a free copy over Instagram. This was an uplifting and rewarding project to work on during such an unusual time. https://powkidsbooks.com/books/the-big-hug/ (link)

Volunteering

Social Media Assistant (SCBWI) - Words & Pictures Magazine (2018-2021)

In this voluntary role I assisted in organizing and scheduling social media posts to help promote Words & Pictures, the online magazine for members of the SCBWI. I set a weekly schedule for posts to publish across Facebook and Twitter (using Tweetdeck), which would consist of a 'round up' of all the new articles on Sunday and then publishing a separate post for each article across the week. I would also compile a weekly e-mail newsletter using Mailchimp. I enjoyed this position and found it an interesting insight into how social media is used from the point of view of an organization.

Education

University of Birmingham - Frontend Skills Bootcamp UX/UI Design - 2023 (Certificate to be completed)

University of Gloucestershire - 2011-2014 BA (Hons) Illustration 2:1

Stourbridge College, West Midlands - 2010-2011 Foundation Diploma in Art and Design

King Edwards VI College, Stourbridge, West Midlands - 2008-2010 A-levels – English Language and Literature – A, History – A, Art and Design – C

Perryfields High School, Oldbury, West Midlands - 2003-2008 10 G.C.S.E's A*-B, including English and Maths